
Usage:   
  pip install [options] <requirement specifier> [package-index-options] ...
  pip install [options] -r <requirements file> [package-index-options] ...
  pip install [options] [-e] <vcs project url> ...
  pip install [options] [-e] <local project path> ...
  pip install [options] <archive url/path> ...

Description:
  Install packages from:
  
  - PyPI (and other indexes) using requirement specifiers.
  - VCS project urls.
  - Local project directories.
  - Local or remote source archives.
  
  pip also supports installing from "requirements files", which provide
  an easy way to specify a whole environment to be installed.

Install Options:
  -r, --requirement <file>    Install from the given requirements file. This
                              option can be used multiple times.
  -c, --constraint <file>     Constrain versions using the given constraints
                              file. This option can be used multiple times.
  --build-constraint <file>   Constrain build dependencies using the given
                              constraints file. This option can be used
                              multiple times.
  --no-deps                   Don't install package dependencies.
  --pre                       Include pre-release and development versions. By
                              default, pip only finds stable versions.
  -e, --editable <path/url>   Install a project in editable mode (i.e.
                              setuptools "develop mode") from a local project
                              path or a VCS url.
  --dry-run                   Don't actually install anything, just print what
                              would be. Can be used in combination with
                              --ignore-installed to 'resolve' the
                              requirements.
  -t, --target <dir>          Install packages into <dir>. By default this
                              will not replace existing files/folders in
                              <dir>. Use --upgrade to replace existing
                              packages in <dir> with new versions.
  --platform <platform>       Only use wheels compatible with <platform>.
                              Defaults to the platform of the running system.
                              Use this option multiple times to specify
                              multiple platforms supported by the target
                              interpreter.
  --python-version <python_version>
                              The Python interpreter version to use for wheel
                              and "Requires-Python" compatibility checks.
                              Defaults to a version derived from the running
                              interpreter. The version can be specified using
                              up to three dot-separated integers (e.g. "3" for
                              3.0.0, "3.7" for 3.7.0, or "3.7.3"). A major-
                              minor version can also be given as a string
                              without dots (e.g. "37" for 3.7.0).
  --implementation <implementation>
                              Only use wheels compatible with Python
                              implementation <implementation>, e.g. 'pp',
                              'jy', 'cp',  or 'ip'. If not specified, then the
                              current interpreter implementation is used.  Use
                              'py' to force implementation-agnostic wheels.
  --abi <abi>                 Only use wheels compatible with Python abi
                              <abi>, e.g. 'pypy_41'. If not specified, then
                              the current interpreter abi tag is used. Use
                              this option multiple times to specify multiple
                              abis supported by the target interpreter.
                              Generally you will need to specify
                              --implementation, --platform, and --python-
                              version when using this option.
  --user                      Install to the Python user install directory for
                              your platform. Typically ~/.local/, or
                              %APPDATA%\Python on Windows. (See the Python
                              documentation for site.USER_BASE for full
                              details.)
  --root <dir>                Install everything relative to this alternate
                              root directory.
  --prefix <dir>              Installation prefix where lib, bin and other
                              top-level folders are placed. Note that the
                              resulting installation may contain scripts and
                              other resources which reference the Python
                              interpreter of pip, and not that of
                              ``--prefix``. See also the ``--python`` option
                              if the intention is to install packages into
                              another (possibly pip-free) environment.
  --src <dir>                 Directory to check out editable projects into.
                              The default in a virtualenv is "<venv
                              path>/src". The default for global installs is
                              "<current dir>/src".
  -U, --upgrade               Upgrade all specified packages to the newest
                              available version. The handling of dependencies
                              depends on the upgrade-strategy used.
  --upgrade-strategy <upgrade_strategy>
                              Determines how dependency upgrading should be
                              handled [default: only-if-needed]. "eager" -
                              dependencies are upgraded regardless of whether
                              the currently installed version satisfies the
                              requirements of the upgraded package(s). "only-
                              if-needed" -  are upgraded only when they do not
                              satisfy the requirements of the upgraded
                              package(s).
  --force-reinstall           Reinstall all packages even if they are already
                              up-to-date.
  -I, --ignore-installed      Ignore the installed packages, overwriting them.
                              This can break your system if the existing
                              package is of a different version or was
                              installed with a different package manager!
  --ignore-requires-python    Ignore the Requires-Python information.
  --no-build-isolation        Disable isolation when building a modern source
                              distribution. Build dependencies specified by
                              PEP 518 must be already installed if this option
                              is used.
  --check-build-dependencies  Check the build dependencies.
  --break-system-packages     Allow pip to modify an EXTERNALLY-MANAGED Python
                              installation
  -C, --config-settings <settings>
                              Configuration settings to be passed to the build
                              backend. Settings take the form KEY=VALUE. Use
                              multiple --config-settings options to pass
                              multiple keys to the backend.
  --compile                   Compile Python source files to bytecode
  --no-compile                Do not compile Python source files to bytecode
  --no-warn-script-location   Do not warn when installing scripts outside PATH
  --no-warn-conflicts         Do not warn about broken dependencies
  --no-binary <format_control>
                              Do not use binary packages. Can be supplied
                              multiple times, and each time adds to the
                              existing value. Accepts either ":all:" to
                              disable all binary packages, ":none:" to empty
                              the set (notice the colons), or one or more
                              package names with commas between them (no
                              colons). Note that some packages are tricky to
                              compile and may fail to install when this option
                              is used on them.
  --only-binary <format_control>
                              Do not use source packages. Can be supplied
                              multiple times, and each time adds to the
                              existing value. Accepts either ":all:" to
                              disable all source packages, ":none:" to empty
                              the set, or one or more package names with
                              commas between them. Packages without binary
                              distributions will fail to install when this
                              option is used on them.
  --prefer-binary             Prefer binary packages over source packages,
                              even if the source packages are newer.
  --require-hashes            Require a hash to check each requirement
                              against, for repeatable installs. This option is
                              implied when any package in a requirements file
                              has a --hash option.
  --progress-bar <progress_bar>
                              Specify whether the progress bar should be used.
                              In 'auto' mode, --quiet will suppress all
                              progress bars. [auto, on, off, raw] (default:
                              auto)
  --root-user-action <root_user_action>
                              Action if pip is run as a root user [warn,
                              ignore] (default: warn)
  --report <file>             Generate a JSON file describing what pip did to
                              install the provided requirements. Can be used
                              in combination with --dry-run and --ignore-
                              installed to 'resolve' the requirements. When -
                              is used as file name it writes to stdout. When
                              writing to stdout, please combine with the
                              --quiet option to avoid mixing pip logging
                              output with JSON output.
  --group <[path:]group>      Install a named dependency-group from a
                              "pyproject.toml" file. If a path is given, the
                              name of the file must be "pyproject.toml".
                              Defaults to using "pyproject.toml" in the
                              current directory.
  --no-clean                  Don't clean up build directories.

Package Index Options:
  -i, --index-url <url>       Base URL of the Python Package Index (default
                              https://pypi.org/simple). This should point to a
                              repository compliant with PEP 503 (the simple
                              repository API) or a local directory laid out in
                              the same format.
  --extra-index-url <url>     Extra URLs of package indexes to use in addition
                              to --index-url. Should follow the same rules as
                              --index-url.
  --no-index                  Ignore package index (only looking at --find-
                              links URLs instead).
  -f, --find-links <url>      If a URL or path to an html file, then parse for
                              links to archives such as sdist (.tar.gz) or
                              wheel (.whl) files. If a local path or file://
                              URL that's a directory, then look for archives
                              in the directory listing. Links to VCS project
                              URLs are not supported.

General Options:
  -h, --help                  Show help.
  --debug                     Let unhandled exceptions propagate outside the
                              main subroutine, instead of logging them to
                              stderr.
  --isolated                  Run pip in an isolated mode, ignoring
                              environment variables and user configuration.
  --require-virtualenv        Allow pip to only run in a virtual environment;
                              exit with an error otherwise.
  --python <python>           Run pip with the specified Python interpreter.
  -v, --verbose               Give more output. Option is additive, and can be
                              used up to 3 times.
  -V, --version               Show version and exit.
  -q, --quiet                 Give less output. Option is additive, and can be
                              used up to 3 times (corresponding to WARNING,
                              ERROR, and CRITICAL logging levels).
  --log <path>                Path to a verbose appending log.
  --no-input                  Disable prompting for input.
  --keyring-provider <keyring_provider>
                              Enable the credential lookup via the keyring
                              library if user input is allowed. Specify which
                              mechanism to use [auto, disabled, import,
                              subprocess]. (default: auto)
  --proxy <proxy>             Specify a proxy in the form
                              scheme://[user:passwd@]proxy.server:port.
  --retries <retries>         Maximum attempts to establish a new HTTP
                              connection. (default: 5)
  --timeout <sec>             Set the socket timeout (default 15 seconds).
  --exists-action <action>    Default action when a path already exists:
                              (s)witch, (i)gnore, (w)ipe, (b)ackup, (a)bort.
  --trusted-host <hostname>   Mark this host or host:port pair as trusted,
                              even though it does not have valid or any HTTPS.
  --cert <path>               Path to PEM-encoded CA certificate bundle. If
                              provided, overrides the default. See 'SSL
                              Certificate Verification' in pip documentation
                              for more information.
  --client-cert <path>        Path to SSL client certificate, a single file
                              containing the private key and the certificate
                              in PEM format.
  --cache-dir <dir>           Store the cache data in <dir>.
  --no-cache-dir              Disable the cache.
  --disable-pip-version-check
                              Don't periodically check PyPI to determine
                              whether a new version of pip is available for
                              download. Implied with --no-index.
  --no-color                  Suppress colored output.
  --use-feature <feature>     Enable new functionality, that may be backward
                              incompatible.
  --use-deprecated <feature>  Enable deprecated functionality, that will be
                              removed in the future.
  --resume-retries <resume_retries>
                              Maximum attempts to resume or restart an
                              incomplete download. (default: 5)
